He'll have to kick some butt to save his own.
Big Stan is a comedy, crime film directed by Rob Schneider.
A weak con man panics when he learns he's going to prison for fraud.
He hires a mysterious martial arts guru who helps transform him into a martial
arts expert who can fight off inmates who want to hurt or love him.
Big Stan, played by Rob Schneider.
The Master, played by David Carradine.
Madame Foreman, played by Sally Kirkland.
Mindy, played by Jennifer Morrison.
Warden Gasque, played by Scott Wilson.
Mal, played by Richard Kind.
Big Stan is a 2007 American martial arts prison comedy film starring, produced, and directed by Rob
Schneider in his directorial debut with help from his company From Out of Nowhere Productions.
The rest of the cast includes Jennifer Morrison, Scott Wilson, Henry
Gibson, Richard Kind, Sally Kirkland, Jackson Rathbone, M.
Emmet Walsh, Dan Haggerty, and David Carradine.
It tells the story of a real estate con artist who gets sentenced to three years in prison and spends
the six months beforehand getting trained by a martial arts guru to survive in prison.
This film was Gibson's final role before his death in 2009
(the year in which Carradine also died).
Although released in some markets during the fall of 2008, it was released
straight to DVD in the United States on March 24, 2009.
It debuted at number 17 on the DVD rental charts of March 23–30, 2009.
The film explores themes of prison, martial arts, corruption, anti hero, fraud.
The tone is lighthearted.